何だ？　てめぇら 今日は俺達の貸し切りだ　帰んな！ 相談をしに来たんだ この街を出て行ってくれないか。
Why?!
うぉ。 ダメだ　こいつ あの程度の「練」に 時間かかり過ぎ
Insult x And x Payback
結構　力あるじゃねえか！
I'm going to have to refuse. Right now, I'm not in the mood.
うわ　やめろ！
Come on, don't say that.
俺の負けだ　離してくれ！
Just think of it as bad luck that I found you!
ヘヘヘ…。
Let me test my new technique on you.
説明したろ？ この外に出たら負けだ。
That hurts, man... You don't have to give me such a dirty look.
それ以外は　たとえ本人が 「負けた」と言っても 負けじゃ　ねえ。
The one I really want to fight
is someone else, you know.
お前も　一度　俺を蹴り 炎の外へ出た。
That guy with sunglasses,
carrying the big pipe.
お前は負けだ。
Aren't you with him?
はっ！　しまった！ ちょっとタンマ！　もう１回！
Then, why don't you go and find him?
やめとけ　ゴン。
I know where he is.
お前　必殺技 使う気なんだろうけど
But I can't get to him.
必殺技は　こんな大勢の前で 見せるもんじゃ　ない。
He controls smoke, and he's hidden
himself behind a smokescreen.
どうした？　今度は２人がかりか？ ちょっと　もらうね。
I climbed up to the roof, to see
if I could get in from above...
まさか…！
And I happened to spot you.
うわ！
So I'm supposed to be the warm-up
before your main fight?
うぅ…　うぁ！ うぅ…。
Bingo!
はい　俺の勝ち。 フ　フ　フ…。
I've had it for today...
この…。
Will you listen to what I have to say?
クソガキが!!
For the first time since taking
over the family business, I may have killed someone who wasn't my target.
てめぇが約束したことだろ キレてんじゃねえよ。
Dude, my technique is awesome!
ああ　悪かったよ。
Don't be too shocked when you see it.
ついて来な　ボスに会わせてやる。
Well, you'll still be shocked in the end...
へぇ　ここにボスがね。 ボス　客ですぜ。
You should watch your back.
誰だ　そいつら。
What an old trick! I won't fall for that!
追い出す？
Your buddy told me to keep
my eyes on my oppone—
お前達が勝てば この島を出て行こう。 ただし　勝負のやり方は 俺達が決める　どうだ？
Well, the result would have
been the same either way.
ここにいるメンバーが　それぞれ 得意なスポーツで勝負を挑む。
Should I have spared him?
１人１勝 先に８勝したほうが勝ちだ。
Not necessary.
まずは俺が１番手 テーマは　ボクシング。 さぁ　誰がやるんだ？
How's Killua doing? Hmm? He's matured.
俺がやる。
And I believe that he's removed Illumi's needle.
一つだけ特別ルールがある。
I see.
「念」で作り出したものなら 道具もあり。
Oh, that's right...
何だと！ そんなのボクシングじゃ　ねえ！
I had a rare experience today.
安心しろよ　俺は　この拳だけ。
My time was compressed!
それは おたくらのためのルールさ。 誰かと交代するかい？
I must remember to ignore
half of everything you say.
大体　察しはつくぜ。
Okay, we should be safe here.
なぜ　あんたがボクシングで 勝負を挑んで来たかな！
Explain what's going on.
うっ！
God's Accomplice... Undo!
あんたも放出系だろ？ 限られたエリアの中で　しかも 敵と距離をとりつつ戦える。
Shoot's out of the battle,
and Knuckle is fighting Youpi alone. I need your help...
放出系にとって これほど都合のいいルールはない。
Knuckle's going to keep running,
to try and buy time.
あんたの誤算は　ただ一つ。
He's crazy!
この俺の能力が あんたより上だってこと！
Okay, what's the minimum length of time
you can maintain God's Accomplice?
すげぇ！ あれは　よけきれねえ！ うぅ…　グッ…。
The first time, I was so nervous, I failed
and had to tap out after ten seconds.
よし　ダウンだ！　楽勝！
If I don't move, I can hold my
breath for at least a minute!
いや　相打ちだよ。 はぁ？ あぁ…
That's plenty of time. I just need one chance.
一体　何が起きたんだ…。 なぜ…。
Approximately three minutes
before Killua raised his finger...
瞬間移動だよ。 瞬間移動？
Knuckle was airborne.
気絶しているようだ まずは俺達の１勝だな。 クソっ！ チッ。 こいつらのレベルでは ８勝は無理　ならば…
Once, to help his friends escape, he knocked out a cop, and eluded four patrol cars and dozens
of police for a full day and night, on foot.
さぁ　次は俺だ テーマは　リフティング。
The day he finally escaped was the day
次は俺が…。 待て　ゴン。 えっ？
he graduated from grade school.
はい！　次は私がやります。
His stamina when maintaining top speed
ケガをさせないように 気をつけなきゃな。
far exceeds that of a cheetah.
リフティングでケガ？
To save Shoot, Knuckle had chosen
フッ 「念」での攻撃がありだからな。 手で球を触る以外はね。
to reveal himself and use an out-boxing
strategy against Youpi.
なるほどね。
For the most part, it was the right choice.
先にボールが 床に落ちてしまったほうの負け。
He stopped chasing me?
はい　分かりました。 ＯＫ　じゃあ　始めようか。
If there was one thing he miscalculated,
it was his opponent's intentions.
レディー　ゴー！
Shoot's in trouble! Crap!
あっ！ 思ったより難しいですね　これ。 私の負けです。
Shoot and Knuckle considered
Youpi a high-priority target.
じゃあ　次は俺だ　おっさん　やる？
But Youpi wasn't as focused on them.
当たり前だ！　覚悟しろよ　小僧！
As a Royal Guard, protecting the
King was his mission.
はっけよい　のこった！ たたきつぶしてやる！
His focus was on keeping enemies from the King.
あっ　悪ぃ　悪ぃ　外に出ちまった。 なるほど　そういうことか
Youpi still believed the King
to be in the throne room. And since guarding the stairway
was his assignment, he was convinced that Pitou and
Pouf were protecting the King.
これで８勝目　俺達の勝ちだ。 出直して来な。 この街は 俺達の好きにさせてもらうぜ。
So his main priority was to keep enemies
away from the throne room.
てめぇ！　小僧！　戻って来い！ もう一度　勝負だ！
Since he didn't know how
many enemies there were, the nature of his opponent's
ability took second priority.
このメンバーじゃ 勝てないとみるや わざと負けて 情報収集に切り替えるとはな。
Hey! Pitou!
ボマー組の コンプリート阻止という
Shoot!
当初の目的は達成できたわ。 あいつらに １５人の仲間を集めるのは
Shoot was still alive.
まず不可能だからね。 あんた達も　しばらく このイベント　ほっといたら？
Shoot...
俺達にとっても　このカードは なるべく早く 入手したほうがいいんだ。
Then we aren't even worth...
少しでも仲間割れの危険を 回避するため。
finishing off?
その通り。 えっ？ 仲間は最低１５人必要。
Youpi didn't care if Shoot lived or died.
でも「クローン」を使っても 「一坪の海岸線」のカード化限度枚数は たったの３枚。
After having fought him with all they had, the pair had never felt so humiliated.
このイベントは　初めから仲間同士の 争いの火種を抱えているんだよ。
Are Shoot
あぁ…。 あぁ…。
and I
あんたが言った あの言葉の意味…。
no more than flies?!
)
Fine, then!
最初　分かんなくて考えたからね。
You're gonna regret this!
俺達　全員が勝つことを 前提にしても 最低　あと４人の手だれがいる。
In a few more minutes,
this fly will send you flying!
理想は　そいつらが１１人組の パーティーってことだが
Pitou! Pouf!
誰か心当たりはないか？ ブック。
Are you there?
リストの名前だけでいったら 一番強いのは　やっぱりクロロかな。
The boss used Smoky Jail on the throne room. That means he and Pouf are alone inside.
でも　クラピカが　１００％ 偽者だって言ってたからなぁ。
The King isn't in the throne room!
じゃあ　誰なんだろ？ まぁ　「旅団」の誰かだろうな。
Say something! Can't you hear me?
「旅団」のメンバーだとして その目的は？
Hey!
そりゃあ ゲームクリアじゃねえの？
You fool...
だったら　自分の名前で 構わないじゃん。
You're free to defend an empty throne room!
そうだな。 「サイトビジョン」を使ってみろよ。 えっ？ そいつが ゲームクリア以外の目的なら
I'll take Shoot, and watch from a safe distance.
カード集めに興味がないのかも。 あぁ　そうか。
Damn it...
持ってるカードは全て 水と食料だけだ。 だったら　仲間に 誘いやすいんじゃないか？ でも　もしも 「旅団」のメンバーだったら
By the time Knuckle realized his mistake, he had already made another.
仲間にはしないよ　話を聞くだけ。 なら　わざわざ 確認する必要ねえって。
Shoot and Youpi must have seen one another.
ぜってぇ　奴らの誰かだし。 誰かもそうだけど　理由のほうも 知りたいんだってば。
Shoot must have been prepared
to die at that moment.
バカか　おめぇはよ！ 理由って そいつに直接　聞くのか？
That's the kind of fight we came for.
あいつらが教えてくれるわけ ねえだろうが！ あぁ　バカですよだ！
But he ignored Shoot...
バカだから 分かってても確かめたいの！ んじゃ　勝手にしろ！ あぁ　勝手にするさ！
When Knuckle pictured the
expression on Youpi's face
大丈夫か？ 日常茶飯事ですので。 じゃあ　行くよ！ いいから　さっさとやれよ。 ガルルル…。 ガルルル…。
after he'd glanced at the bloody Shoot
and headed up to the third floor, Knuckle realized his new mistake.
「アカンパニー」オン！ クロロ＝ルシルフル！
Damn it. Damn it...
あっ！
And if our mission succeeds,
I just shake Shoot's hand and say, "We did it"?
まさか…。 ヒソカ！
Even though he was humiliated?
ん？
I can't do that!
あっ…。 おやおや これは予期せぬ　お客さんだ。
That isn't right...
フフフ…　やっぱりそうだ。
C-Come on... Oh, sorry.
ずいぶん 成長したんじゃないかい？ いい師に巡り合えたようだね。
And while I'm apologizing, I need
you to wait here a little longer!
僕の見込んだ通り 君達は　どんどん　おいしく実る。
I need to punch that guy in the face...
何なんだ　この変態野郎は！ 君かい？　彼らの先生は。
And I'll throw another punch for you!
はっ！　キャ　イヤン！ 彼女か で　僕…　というより クロロに何の用？
It's my job to stay calm and stop Knuckle... "Have you lost your mind?
聞きたいことがあるんだ。
Don't go.
ここへ何しに来たの？
Just keep your mouth shut, and buy more time."
さて　どうするか… 話せば　この２人のことだ
That is my...
「クモ」との除念師の引き渡しを 全力で阻止しにかかるだろうな
Do it, Knuckle!
それはそれで面白いんだけど
Damn it!
これ以上　クロロとの戦いを 延ばされるのも勘弁だな
That bastard... He... He...
クロロを捜してるんだ。
looked at me like I was trash!
クロロが クラピカに　かけられた「念」 実は　外す方法があるんだ。
Give that bastard an extra punch for me...
何だ… 知ってたのなら話が早い。
Yeah, I got it!
それをクロロに教えたくて 捜してるんだけど 手掛かりなくてね。
Sorry, master...
そんな時　「クモ」の何人かが
We're both fools.
このゲームに興味を 持ってたことを思い出した。 彼らなら　クロロの行き先に
There's something more important
than the world right now!
何か心当たりが あるんじゃないかと思ってさ。
Knuckle's new mistake
この名前なら　あっちからの アプローチも期待できるしね。
was a misjudgment of his priorities.
まさか　その質問をするためだけに ここへ来たわけじゃないだろ？ ううん　そうだよ。
My attacks aren't having any
effect on this smoke...
あの…。
Your Majesty!
実は私達　できるだけ強い人を 探してるんです。
Pitou! Pouf! Are you there? Hey!
仲間になっていただけませんか？
Is that Youpi?
ん？　いいけど 強い人を探してる理由は？
Were they both defeated?
ちょっと待てよ 俺は反対だな　危険だぜ。
I hope the old man's doing okay...
そうだよ！ ビスケは　あいつを知らねえから。
Why isn't Pouf responding?
あの方には　何か 近しいものを感じますもの。
Why is he staying inside his cocoon?
この先にある　恋愛都市アイアイに 行くといいんじゃない？
I would have expected him to be in
more of a hurry to get to the King.
いろんな出会いが楽しめるから 強い人も見つかるかもしれないよ。
Could we have made... some kind of mistake about the Royal Guard?
ウソをついてるって どういうことだよ。
Is our operation actually working?
正確に言うと　本当のことを 言ってないって感じね。 何で分かんの？ そんなもん勘だわさ。
Don't think about it! I'm here to fulfill my mission!
勘かよ！ ５０年以上　ウソつきやってると 分かるもんなのさ！ ホホホ…！
Doubt, worry, impatience...
何か　すげぇ説得力あんな…。 奴が何か隠している以上
Negative emotions are growing,
but his resolve has not faltered.
身近に置いて 様子を見るのも一つのて。
Just as I would expect from a strong fighter.
何より　あいつ かなり強いでしょ？
I'm impressed.
うん。
However, that will be the constraint
that weakens your decision-making.
うっ！ うっ！ おい　ヒソカ！　前を歩けよ！
Why is Pitou's En gone?
あと１０人　仲間がいるんだよね？
Have the King, Pitou, and Pouf all vanished? Leaving me behind?
ああ　できれば　あんたみたく
What happened?
カードに 執着のない人物がいいんだが。
What's going on?
みんな　ここにクリア目的で 来てるんだろう？
It's time. Adding interest.
僕みたいな酔狂なプレーヤーは 少ないんじゃないの？
Shut up!
やっぱり　どうも 何か隠してるわね
The black fog on my shoulder won't go away. And the number on this thing keeps increasing.
ところで　さっき ４人で飛んで来たのって
I have to find the King!
誰かの能力かい？
Damn, I should have killed the fly downstairs.
あれは　このゲームのスペルだよ。
That might have gotten rid of this fog.
あぁ　あれがそうなんだ。 確か　店で 買わなきゃいけないんだよね。
But I have to find the King! What's going on?!
確かに　何か引っかかる… 本当のことを言っていない
I'm getting annoyed!
「クモ」のメンバーを捜して ここに来た この言葉の中に そのカギが隠されている！
Yo.
うわ！　メガネ　メガネ…。
What the hell is wrong with all of you?!
拾ってあげたら？ 知り合いになれるよ。
And with that shout, Youpi transformed.
うわ！　ちょっと！ どこ見て歩いてんのよ。 気をつけてよね！ すまん。 あ！　遅刻しちゃう！
It was drastic enough to make Knuckle,
who thought he had come prepared, instantly switch from an offensive
stance to an evasive one.
ダメだよ　謝っちゃ。 「そっちこそ気をつけろ！」　とか 口ゲンカしないとね　今のコとは。
This manifestation of evil
やめてください！ 離して！　大声出すわよ！
clearly meant only to destroy.
そうかい？ ここなら退屈せずに済むのに。
Hang on!
退屈…
Did you... hit him?
分かった！ 何が　しっくり来なかったかが…
Eh? Did you hit him...
場所…　この場所だ！
for me? Not yet, damn it!
このゲームの中に 誰かを捜しに来たとしたら
I'll hit him hard, so hold on!
俺なら　どうした？ まずは　スペルカードの重要性に 気づいたはずだ
But we have to run, so we don't die first!
そう！　普通なら マサドラから動かない スペルカードを求めて　ほとんどの プレーヤーがやって来るから
For the first time in his life, Youpi had endured an excessive amount of stress.
本当に「旅団」の連中を 捜しているなら
This had made it apparent that
マサドラから動かないはず )
his power was not meant for guarding the King.
退屈している… やることがない
Rather, he realized that his violent rage
つまり捜していない… いや　もう捜し終えている！
could fuel a rapid increase in the
mass of both his body and his aura.
それだ！　それなら ビスケの言ったこととニュアンスも合う ヒソカは　すでに奴らと会って ここで何かを待っている 何を待ってる…　決まってる！
The destruction brought him great pleasure, after which his body rapidly shrank,
and he felt a strong sense of loss.
除念師！　除念師は　ここ 『グリードアイランド』にいる！ それをヒソカも「旅団」の奴らも 知ってるんだ
Knuckle's superior experience helped him
understand what had happened to Youpi. We can win.
まだ　ゴンには言えない こいつは隠すのが下手だ
That was a powerful blast.
もし俺達が気づいたことに ヒソカが気づけば 奴は姿を消す そうすれば 仲間が１人減る上に
I doubt it'll be easy to goad him
into doing that on purpose, and make it out unharmed.
「旅団」の動向も分からなくなる
But the return for taking that risk
それだけは避けなきゃ ねぇ　キルア　考えたんだけど
will be enormous.
仲間にするなら やっぱり　ツェズゲラだと思うんだ。
I make him mad, so he blows up.
仲間にしないまでも 一度　会っておいて
The perfect time to hit him
バインダーのリストに 入れといたほうが…。
would be when he's charging up.
あっちの動向も知れて 便利だもんな。
And the aura required to fuel his explosion
バインダー… 確かめることができる！
will cause him to go bankrupt sooner.
ヒソカ　バインダー見せてよ！ ヒソカが会ったプレーヤーの リストの中に
The plan Knuckle formed on the spot
ツェズゲラって人が いるかどうか見てほしいんだ。 リスト？
was almost flawless for dealing
with the berserk Youpi.
ある意味ナイス！ 俺が探りを入れたら ヒソカに気づかれる危険があった
However, Youpi's true worth only
became clear after the explosion.
だが　事情を知らないゴンなら ヒソカに気づかれることはない ブック。 ヒソカが 画面を見せようとしなければ
As Youpi transitioned between
lingering pleasure and despondency, this selfish ability that could be
called the dregs of his ego
俺の考えが裏付けられる ツェズゲラ　いるね。
was focused solely on how he could use
ホント？ うん　ほら　ここ。
this power for the King's sake.
えっ！
Selflessness...
見せた？　ばかな！ 「旅団」の名前が…　ない
His Ant instincts and Magical Beast mentality
俺の考え過ぎだったか
continued to function calmly even after
the discovery of his burst of emotion.
やはり　ヒソカは ただ奴らを捜しているだけ…
My contribution to the King will be
じゃあヒソカ　これ唱えてくれる？ 交渉は　俺達がやるから。
how well I can control this ability
without letting my emotions take over.
フフフフ　やっぱり便利 僕の「ドッキリテクスチャー」
In other words, I must use it to destroy the intruders.
ヒソカの能力に 見事に　だまされたキルア達
Now that Youpi had learned how
to be both enraged and composed, the risk for Knuckle was overly great.
果たして　ヒソカは敵か味方か
Approximately three minutes have
passed since the mission began.